至今我的生活是这样的:
Here's my day so far:
蹲过大牢 失去过梦中情人
Went to jail, lost the girl of my dreams,
被狠狠扁过
and got my butt kicked pretty good.
仍然 事情变得更加糟糕
Still, things could be a lot worse.
噢 对了
Oh, that's right.
我就要摔成肉饼了
I'm falling to my death.
不是吧
Guess they can't.
你也许会问 怎会如此结局?
How'd it all come to this, you ask?
结局早已是注定的
My end starts at the beginning.
从最初就注定了
The very beginning.
是的 那就是我
Yes, that's me.
我有一个非常正常的童年
I had a fairly standard childhood.
我出生于 你们所说的破碎的家庭
I came from, what you might call, a broken home.
字面意义上的破碎
Literally broken.
我在八天大的时候 我还和我的双亲在一起
I was eight days old and still living with my parents.
很悲剧吧
How sad is that?
显然这个时候该改变了
Clearly it was time to move on.
这是你的跟班 他会照顾你的
Here is your minion. He will take care of you.
还有 这个是你的奶嘴
And here is your binky.
你的命运是...
You are destined for...
我没有听清楚最后的那一部分 不过听起来很重要
I didn't quite hear that last part, but it sounded important.
...二 一 - 命运是啥?
...two, one. - Destined for what?
我出发去寻找我的人生
I set out to find my destiny.
另一个格兰普象限的小鬼与我的想法完全一致
Turns out a kid from the Glaupunkt quadrant had the exact same idea.
就是那天我遇到了大好人先生...
That was the day I met Mr. Goody Two- Shoes...
...那时我们闪亮的人生轨迹开始了
...and our glorious rivalry was born.
难道这个就是我命运?
Could this be what I was destined for?
奢华的梦幻般的生活
A dream life filled with luxury.
显然不是的
Apparently not.
就连命运也会按喜好挑选
Even fate picks its favorites.
没啥
No big deal.
一个截然不同的人生等着我
A much different fate awaited me.
宝宝 真体贴
A baby! How thoughtful.
噢 是的 是的 我看到了它就想到了你
Oh, yes. Yes, I saw it and thought of you.
幸运的是 我找到了一个小小的一个叫家的地方
Luckily I found a lovely little place to call home.
我们能留下它么
Can we keep it?
这个地方教育我对和错
A place that taught me the differences between right...
的区别
...and wrong.
大好人先生
Mr. Goody Two- Shoes, on the other hand,
过着衣来伸手饭来张口的日子
had life handed to him on a silver platter.
我们的宝宝会飞呀
Our baby can fly.
是的 是的 你的宝宝最强了 亲爱的
Yes, yes, nothing but the best for you, darling.
飞行能力 刀枪不入 无敌发型
The power of flight, invulnerability, and great hair.
我又更加更加强的本领
But I had something far, far greater.
强大的智慧......
My amazing intellect...
...我有能制造破坏力超强的工具
...and knack for building objects of mayhem.
在几年的良好表现后
After a few years, and with some time off for good behavior,
我有机会能继续深造了...
I was given an opportunity to better myself through learning...
...通过一个叫学校的奇怪地方
...at a strange place called shool.
在那里我再次遇到了大好人先生
It was there that I once again ran into Mr. Goody Two- Shoes.
在那里他已经有了他的脑残粉丝团了
He had already amassed a gigantic army of soft- headed groupies.
他用美味食物
He bought their affections with showmanship
收买友情
and extravagant gifts of deliciousness.
所以我也要做爆米花 然后赢得这群盲目份子的喜爱
So I, too, will make this popp- ed corn and win over those mindless drones.
熄灯
Lights out.
从那时我学到了艰辛的一课:
That's when I learned a very hard lesson:
好人总是受到爱戴
Good receives all the praise and adulation,
干坏事的就是要去蹲墙角
while evil is sent to quiet- time in the corner.
看来我无法合群
So fitting in wasn't really an option.
当他们在学唱儿歌时...
While they were learning the Itsy Bitsy Spider...
...我在学习如何将生物脱水然后再按照意愿水化它们
...I learned how to dehydrate animate objects and rehydrate them at will.
有些时候 觉得只有小跟班和我在一起 与全世界为敌
Some days, it felt like it was just me and Minion against the world.
不管我怎么努力
No matter how hard I tried,
我永远都不合群
I was always the odd man out,
是剩下的那个
the last one picked,
永远一团糟 是老鼠屎
the screw- up, the black sheep...
瞄准他!
Get him!
...坏孩子 - 怪胎!
...the bad boy. - Freak!
傻逼!
Weirdo!
这就是我的命运吗?
Was this my destiny?
等等 也许没错
Wait, maybe it was.
当坏蛋不就是我最拿手的吗
Being bad is the one thing I'm good at.
我恍然大悟 如果我是个坏孩子
Then it hit me: If I was the bad boy,
我就要当最坏的那个
then I was going to be the baddest boy of them all.
我命中注定会成为超级大坏蛋
I was destined to be a super- villain,
我们生来就是对手
and we were destined to be rivals.
生死已注定
The die had been cast,
我那不朽史诗般的终身事业就这样开始了
and so began an enduring, epic, lifelong career.
我爱这份工作
And I loved it.
我们的恩怨越来越错综复杂
Our battles quickly got more elaborate.
他赢了几次
He would win some.
我也不逊色
I would almost win others.
他的名号是曼城卫士 蛮城的守护者
He took the name Metro Man, defender of Metrocity.
我打算取一个低调点的名字 超级大坏蛋
I decided to pick something a little more humble: Megamind...
不可比拟的英俊的犯罪天才 一切罪恶的主人
...incredibly handsome criminal genius and master of all villainy.
超级大坏蛋
下班了再看 开门
Read on your own time. Open up.
- 嘿 - 呸
- Hey! - Boo!
噢 早上好 典狱官
Oh, good morning, Warden.
好消息哦 我改过自新了
Great news: I'm a changed man, and...
作为合格的公民 我可以重返社会了
...and I'm ready to re- enter society as a solid citizen.
你是个恶棍 而且永远是个恶棍
You're a villain, and you'll always be a villain.
你根本没有改过 也就别想着离开
You'll never change, and you'll never leave.
你真搞笑
You're fun.
有人给你寄了份礼物
You got a present in the mail.
是狗狗吗
Is it a puppy?
曼城卫士给你的 "希望你珍惜85次无期徒刑的每分每秒"
From Metro Man. "To count every second of your 85 life sentences."
真好玩 没想到曼城卫士也会幸灾乐祸
That's funny. Never thought Metro Man was the gloating type.
噢 但他品位的确不错 我帮你保管吧
Oh, but he does have nice taste. I think I'll keep it.
能不能不要拖延我的时间了
Any chance you could give me the time?
今天曼城卫士博物馆开放 我不想迟到
I don't want to be late for the opening of the Metro Man Museum.
噢 不 看来你要错过了
Oh no. Looks like you're gonna miss it,
错过好几千年
by several thousand years.
噢 是吗
Oh, am I?
曼城 曼城卫士日快乐
Happy Metro Man Day, Metro City.
在这美丽的日子 美丽的城市
It's a beautiful day in beautiful downtown,
我们有幸向这个美丽的人致敬 曼城卫士
where we're here to honor a beautiful man, Metro Man.
他的心胸似海洋 但更宽广
His heart is an ocean that's inside a bigger ocean.
这些年 他用他的超视力一直看护着我们
For years he's been watching us with his super- vision,
用他的超能力解救我们 用他那超宽广的爱心照顾我们
saving us with his super- strength and caring for us with his super- heart.
现在我们回报他的时候到了
Now it's our turn to give something back.
这里是洛克斯安 瑞驰
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting live
在 曼城卫士博物馆落成典礼现场发回的报道
from the dedication of the Metro Man Museum.
喔 好的 刚才他们让你在广播里念的那一段
Wow. OK, the stuff they make you read on- air,
真难以置信 都疯狂了
that's un- freaking- believable. It's crazy.
那是我自己写的 哈尔
I wrote that piece myself, Hal.
其实我想说的是
What I was trying to say was,
在现代社会里
I can't believe that in our modern society,
还能出现艺术的美感真是难得啊
they let, like, actual art get onto the news.
补救的不错啊 哈尔
- Nice save, Hal. - What are we...
我们去喝杯咖啡什么的吧
Like, let's just get a coffee or something.
拜托 今天是 曼城卫士节的大日子
Come on, it's time to get in the Metro Man Day spirit.
如果我是曼城卫士的话
Well, if I were Metro Man,
决不会让超级大坏蛋 绑架你那么多次
Megamind wouldn't be kidnapping you all the time.
- 这是最最最重要的事 - 你真贴心 哈尔
- That's the first thing. - That's sweet, Hal.
我会像澳洲野犬照顾孩子一样看着你
And I'd be watching you, like a dingo watches a human baby.
好吧 那听起来...
OK, that sounded...
- 好吧 那听起来有点怪 - 是的 确实有一点
- OK, that sounded a little weird. - A little bit. Yeah.
你的鬼脸让我也感到怪怪的
And you're making a weird face, and that's making me feel weird.
重点是 我会看着你就像...
The point is, I would watch you like someone...
不是爱 我们又没恋爱 我不是说我爱你
Not love. We're not in love. I'm not saying I love you.
嘿 不管怎么样 我爱你
Hey, I love you. Whatever.
但是 我又没有说就像我爱着你 我是说...
But I'm not saying like I'm in love with you. I'm saying...
洛克斯安 洛克斯安
Roxanne? Roxaroo?
- 什么...什么 - 嘿...
- Whoa... What? - Hey...
好好上班 政府花钱又不是让你游手好闲的
Get back to work. The city doesn't pay you to loaf.
- 不许动! - 同志们 你们要干什么
- Freeze! - Whoa. What are you doing, guys?
是我 我是典狱官
It's me! It's the warden.
喂 开门
Hey! Open up!
不 你们这些笨蛋 我们被他耍了
No, you fools. He's tricked us.
你说得没错
You were right.
我一直都会是个大坏蛋
I'll always be a villain.
哎呀帅哥 要搭你一程不
Well, hello good- Iooking. Need a lift?
当然要啊 你这条聪明绝顶的鱼
Certainly do, you fantastic fish, you.
- 快上车吧 - 我自由了
- Get in the car, you. - I'm free!
是吗
Right?
你送我的手表太赞了 小跟班
Nice work sending me the watch, Minion.
- 那还用说 老板 - 用力打
- You got it, boss. - Punch it!
成功 大家一起来举起双手
All right, put your hands in the air.
女士们先生们 欢迎曼城卫士
Ladies and gentlemen, your Metro Man!
- 你们在等谁 - 曼城卫士!
- Who's your man? - Metro Man!
是的 曼城!
Yeah, Metro City!
来吧 举高你们的手
Gimme some. Come on. Give it now.
把手都给我 来吧 很好
Give it to me. Right on. Gimme the good stuff. All right.
嘿 曼城
Hey, Metro City.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
你们都知道 你们都知道 我是很低调的
You know, you know, I just want to bring it down a bit.
小伙子们 小点声 谢谢你们 朋友们
Boys, a little lower. Thank you, fellas.
现在来点实际的
Let's get real for a moment.
对的 对的 对的
That's right. That's right. That's right.
尽管有了博物馆是非常非常酷的事情
Although getting a whole museum is super- cool, is super- cool,
但你们知道我最大荣誉是什么吗
you want to know what the greatest honor you've given me is?
你们真的想知道吗 真的吗
Do you really want to know? Really?
那我来告诉你们
I'll tell you.
你们给我的最大荣誉就是...
The greatest honor you've given me is letting me serve you,
...让我为你们服务 帮助曼城的市民
the helpless people of Metro City.
每天结束的时候
And at the end of every day,
我常常问自己
well, I often ask myself...
如果没有你们 我会是谁?
...who would I be without you?
- 我爱你 曼城卫士! - 我也爱你们 市民朋友
- I love you, Metro Man! - And I love you, random citizen.
我跟你说 小跟班 没什么能比得上自己的邪恶老窝了
I tell you, Minion. There's no place like evil lair.
我特地为您保持潮湿阴冷
I've kept it cold and damp just for you, sir.
我看起来怎样 小根班? 我看起来很邪恶不?
How do I look, Minion? Do I look bad?
先生 您恐怖得一塌糊涂
Disgustingly horrifying, sir.
你的小嘴儿越来越甜了
You always know what to say.
噢 我的脑蝇 当然想你们啦
Oh, the brain- bots certainly missed you, sir.
想你们的老爹不 那个最调皮的捣蛋鬼呢
Did you miss your daddy? Who's a menacing little cyborg?
是你啊 是的 就是你 不许咬
You are. Yes, you are. No biting.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
要扳手吗? 去捡回来吧
You want the wrench? Go get the wrench.
- 噢 快看 - 现在欢笑又回来了
- Oh, look at that. - Now, back to laughing.
她快醒了 快准备干活
She's awake. Quick, to work.
瑞驰小姐 我们又见面了
Miss Ritchi, we meet again.
把袋子洗了你会死啊
Would it kill you to wash the bag?
瑞驰小姐你就扯起嗓子喊吧
You can scream all you wish, Miss Ritchi.
你喊破喉咙也不会有人听见的
I'm afraid no one can hear you.
为...为什么你不叫啊
Wh... Why isn't she screaming?
瑞驰小姐 如果你不介意的话
Miss Ritchi, if you don't mind?
就像这样...
Like this...
但是 那是 可怜女士的叫法
But that's, that's a poor lady scream.
他比我擅长些
He's a little better.
这个是不是在那个傻叉超级恶棍网站上
Is there some kind of nerdy super- villain Web site
搞到的特斯拉线圈和闪光按键
where you get Tesla coils and blinky dials?
事实上 大部分都是从...
Actually, most of it comes from an outlet store in...
不要接话
Don't answer that.
- 罗马尼亚买的 - 不要 停
- Romania. - Don't! Stop!
她在用她那记者的小伎俩
She's using her nosy reporter skills
从你不设防的脑袋里 挖掘我们的秘密
on your weak- willed mind to find out all our secrets.
这点小伎俩对我没用
Such tricks won't work on me...
- 能再说慢点吗 - 妖精
- Please talk slower. ...temptress.
你有什么秘密 一眼就看穿了
What secrets? You're so predictable.
看穿了 看穿了
Predictable? Predictable?
噢 你叫这个看穿了
Oh, you call this predictable?
你的短吻鳄嘛 是的
Your alligators. Yes.
耶 在来的路上我就想到了
Yeah, I was thinking about it on the way over.
那这个呢 砰 在你脸上
What's this? Boom! In your face.
- 陈词滥调 - 不 看这个
- Cliche. - No! Look, watch.
- 幼稚 - 震撼吧
- Juvenile. - Shock and awe.
- 没新意 - 噢 这多可怕啊
- Tacky. - Oh, it's so scary!
- 见过了 - 那这个呢
- Seen it. - What's this one do?
浮夸
Garish.
- 好吧 蜘蛛还有点新意 - 蜘蛛?
- OK, the spider's new. - Spider?
是的 蜘蛛
Yes. The... The spee- ider.
即使被这只致命黑寡妇咬一小口
Even the smallest bite from Arachnis deathicus
就会彻底瘫掉...
will instantly paralyze...
帮我赶走 它在咬我
Get it off! It bit me!
放弃吧 超级大坏蛋 你的计划就没成功过
Give it up, Megamind. Your plans never work.
别浪费时间了 赶紧给男朋友打电话吧
Let's stop wasting time and call your boyfriend in tights, shall we?
很荣幸的能把这个新博物馆献给给曼城卫士
It is with great pleasure that I present to Metro Man his new museum.
有请
If you please.
- 曼城卫士! - 嘿 我孩子看不见
- Metro Man! - Hey! My kid can't see.
- 超级大坏蛋 - 噢 好极了 曼城卫士
- Megamind! - Oh, bravo, Metro Man.
呸!
Boo!
没错 我一起玩 呸
Yes, I can play along too. Boo!
我早知道你会来闹场子
Should've known you'd try to crash the party.
噢 不仅仅是闹场子这么简单
Oh, I intend to do more than crash it.
今天会让你和蛮城都会很难忘
This is a day you and Metrocity shall not soon forget.
是读作曼城!
It's pronounced Metro City!
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮
Potato- tomato, potato- tomato.
我们都知道结局会怎么样 那就是你再次入狱
We all know how this ends: With you behind bars.
正在我的海豹皮靴里发抖呢
I'm shaking in my custom baby seal leather boots.
你就要永别蛮城了 不然的话这是你最后一次
You will leave Metrocity, or this will be the last
听到洛克斯安 瑞驰讲话了
you ever hear of Roxanne Ritchi.
洛克斯安 不要慌 洛丝
Roxanne! Don't panic, Roxie.
- 我马上就到 - 是的 我不慌张
- I'm on my way. - Yeah, I'm not panicking.
要想阻止我 你先找到我吧 曼城卫士
In order to stop me, you need to find me first, Metro Man.
我们在废弃的t望台
We're at the abandoned observatory.
不 不是的
No, we're not!
不要听她的 她疯掉了
Don't listen to her. She's crazy.
曼城卫士就要到了 先生
Metro Man approaching, sir.
等等
Hold on a second.
噢 我的天
Oh, good heavens!
你没想到我们是在真的t望台吧
You didn't think you were in the real observatory, did you?
准备发射死亡射线 小跟班
Ready the death ray, Minion.
死亡射线 准备发射
Death ray, readying.
看这里 我的老朋友
Over here, old friend.
友情提醒下 你掉进我的陷阱啦
In case you haven't noticed, you've fallen right into my trap.
你无法打败正义 这是一种理想 一种信念
You can't trap justice. It's an idea, a belief.
就算最虔诚的信念也会被时间所侵蚀
Even the most heartfelt belief can be corroded over time.
正义是耐腐蚀的金属
Justice is a non- corrosive metal.
但是 金属能被复仇的火焰融化
But metals can be melted by the heat of revange.
是仇恨 最好冷冻起来
It's "revenge," and it's best served cold.
但能用微波炉方便的进行加热
But it can be easily reheated in the microwave of evil.
我想保修期快到了吧
Well, I think your warranty is about to expire.
或许我能延长保修期
Maybe I got an extended warranty.
不正确使用该产品保修是无效的
Warranties are invalid if you don't use the product for its intended purpose.
噢 姑娘们 姑娘们 你们都很漂亮 我能回家了不
Oh, girls, girls, you're both pretty. Can I go home now?
当然可以了 如果曼城卫士抗住
Of course. That is, if Metro Man can withstand the full,
太阳的聚光
concentrated power of the sun!
发射
Fire!
小跟班 发射
Minion. Fire?
- 先生 还在预热中 - 你说什么?
- It's still warming up, sir. - Come again?
- 预热中 先生 - 预热中 太阳还要预热
- Warming up, sir. - Warming up? The sun is warming up?
就一下下...
One second more and...
...就一下下 一下下 一下下 下下 下...
...just tippy- tappy tippy- tap- tap, tip- top more,
- 我们马上就准备... - 说实话
- and we are ready in just... - Honestly!
我就来了 洛丝
On my way, Roxie.
都跟你说了 要准备好 都说了无数次了
I told you to have things ready. I told you countless times.
为嘛老是怪我
Why do you always blame me?
蜘蛛毒让我开始抽风
My spider bite is acting up.
你的计划又打了水漂了 承认吧
Your plan is failing. Just admit it.
是啊 希望下次能行
Yeah, good luck with that one.
你站哪边
Whose side are you on?
- 输的一边 - 谢谢
- The losing side. - Thank you.
能给我的绑架贵宾卡上多积一分吗
Could someone stamp my Frequent Kidnapping Card?
这个活动早就到期了
You of all people know we discontinued that promotion.
- 各位 再见了 - 下周老时间见吗
- Ciao- ciao, all! - Same time next week?
见鬼! 金刚罩!
Dag! Crab nuggets!
- 他在讲啥 - 金刚罩
- What did he just say? - "Crab nuggets"?
天啊 我飞不出去
Fackled fish cracker!
还剩十秒
Ten seconds to full power.
- 天呐 我困住了 - 十...
- Good lord, I'm trapped. - Ten...
- 他又搞什么东东 - 九...
- what kind of trickery is this? ...nine...
- 你这个疯子 ...八...
- You mad genius. ...eight...
- 你终于得逞了 ...七...
- Your dark gift has finally paid off. ...seven...
- 有吗? ...六...
- It... It has? ...six...
这个穹顶镀了铜
This dome is obviously lined with copper.
- 是的 怎样 - 先生...
- Yeah? So? - Sir...
- 铜耗尽了我的能量 ...二...
- Copper drains my powers. ...two...
- 你的弱点居然是铜 ...一...
- Your weakness is copper? ...one.
- 开玩笑吧 - 充满
- You're kidding, right? - Full power.
我觉得他这次死翘翘了
I don't think even he could survive that.
还是不抱希望吧
Well, let's not get our hopes up just yet.
- 快快看 - 曼城卫士!
- Look! - Metro Man!
曼城卫士
Metro Man.
曼城卫士!
Metro Man!
- 你做到了 先生 - 我做到了吗
- You... You did it, sir. - I did it?
他做到了
He did it.
- 我做到了 - 他做到了
- I did it? - He did it.
- 你做到了 先生 - 我做到了
- You did it, sir. - I did it!
- 你做到了 - 我做到了 蛮城是我的啦
- You did it! - I did it! Metrocity is mine!
- 你做到了 先生 - 我做到了 是的 我 我
- You did it, sir! - I did it! Yeah, me, me!
- 是的 我做到了 - 我们 我们一起做到了
- Yes, I did it! - Us! We both did it!
- 不是我们 是我 - 你 比我做的
- Not us! I! - You, a little more
- 多那么一点 - 比你多的多
- than me but still, come on! - A lot more than you.
他们什么时候颁奖
When they're giving out the awards,
- 我跟在你后面 - 什么奖 什么奖 为啥颁奖
- I'm gonna be right there next to you. - What awards? What awards, for what?
放音乐
Hit it!
放下武器
Drop 'em!
首先 真是惊天大逆转啊
First off, what a turnout.
很疯狂吧
How wild is this?
我所做的就是铲除了全宇宙最强悍的人
All I did was eliminate the most powerful man in the universe.
还有什么问题吗 是的 后面那位
Are there any questions? Go on. Yes! You in the back.
我肯定大家都想知道 你会怎么处置我们和这座城市
I'm sure we'd all like to know what you plan to do with us and this city.
很好 真高兴你问这个问题
Good, I'm glad you asked that.
想想下你们能想到的最恐怖
Imagine the most horrible, terrifying,
最邪恶的事情
evil thing you can possibly think of,
然后再乘以...六
and multiply it... by six!
同时
In the meantime,
你们可以继续过你们无聊的
I want you to carry on with the dreary, normal things
柴米油盐酱醋茶的生活
you normal people do.
享受这样的生活吧
Let's just have fun with this. Come on.
我会回来的
And I will get back to you.
现在 狠狠地甩门
Now slam the door really hard.
他们...还是能看到你啊
They... They can still see you.
- 现在呢 - 是的 还是能看到啊
- Now? - Your elbow's still in.
很好
Good.
他来了 邪恶之王
There he is, Mr. Evil Overlord
噢 小跟班 你有想过今天吗
Oh, Minion, did you think this day would ever come?
没有 完全没 先生
No way. Not at all, sir.
从没 过个万把年也没... 我的意思是
Never. Never in a million... I mean...
- 是的 我想过 - 看看这精美的吊顶
- Yes, I did. - Look at the intricate mouldings.
在看呢 在看呢
I'm looking. I'm looking.
这是啥
And what's this?
看上去像基地里的大监视器
It's like one of the giant monitors in the lair.
但好像只有一个画面啊
But it seems to only carry one station.
哦 那啊 主人 那个叫做窗户
Oh, that, sir, is called a window.
- 窗户... - 所有孩子从这里往外看
- Window? - All the kids are looking through them.
哦 我以前从没看到过风景
I've never had a view before.
蛮城 小跟班 这都是我的了
Metrocity, Minion, it's all mine.
如果我的父母现在能看到我的话
If my parents could see me now.
先生 我肯定他们在坏蛋的天平向您微笑
Sir, I'm sure they're smiling down from evil heaven.
现在大好人先生被铲除了
And now that Mr. Goody Two- Shoes is out of the way,
我有了我想要的一切了
I can have everything I want,
而且没人能阻止我了
and there's no one to stop me!
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
一直饥渴 永远都得不到满足
Always thirsty, never satisfied.
我能理解 漂亮的小小小小鸟
I understand you, little well- dressed bird.
无目标 空虚啊 都成真空了啊 难道不是吗
Purposeless, emptiness. It's a vacuum, isn't it?
是啊... 你的空虚像什么
It's... What's your vacuum like?
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿 现在不行 小跟班
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Not now, Minion.
我和这死鱼眼的塑料玩具
I'm in a heated, existential discussion
正在进行关于存在的激烈辩论?
with this dead- eyed, plastic desk toy.
有...有什么不对吗 先生
Is... Is something wrong, sir?
想想
Just think about it.
我们有了一切
We have it all.
然而我们一无所有
Yet, we have nothing.
现在没有挑战了
It's just too easy now.
抱歉 我很迷惑 先生
I'm sorry, you've lost me, sir.
我的意思是 我们做到了 不是吗
I mean, we did it, right?
是啊 是你做到了啊
Well, you did it, sir.
是的 你说得非常清楚
Yes, you've made that perfectly clear.
那为什么我感觉这么...这么的不给力呢
Then why do I feel so... mel- on- choly.
不给力
"Mel- on- choly"?
- 不高兴 - 好吧...
- Unhappy. - Well...
那我们明天
What if tomorrow,
去绑架洛克斯安 瑞驰好不
we could go kidnap Roxanne Ritchi.
那一直对您都很给力 您不是一直觉得这样很给力吗
That always seems to lift your spirits.
好主意 小跟班 但没有他 又有什么意思呢
Good idea, Minion. But without him, what's the point?
- 他? 先生? - 没啥
- "Him," sir? - Nothing.
好吧 那么 那就... 当是考虑下吧
OK, all right. We'll just... that's something to consider...
...还有...我想我们先休整下
...and... Well, I think I'll just power down for a while then.
他总是在那里保护我们 那么可依靠
He was always there for us. Dependable.
也许我们认为他就应该这样 你们知道的 也许
Perhaps we took him for granted. You know, maybe,
直到失去我们才懂得他的珍贵
we never really know how good we have it until it's gone.
我们想念你 曼城卫士 我想你
We miss you, Metro Man. I miss you.
我还有一个问题要问超级大坏蛋 现在你满意了吧
And I have just one question for Megamind: Are you happy now?
这是洛克斯安 瑞驰 在没有英雄的城市为您报道
This is Roxanne Ritchi, reporting from a city without a hero.
接下来 你想成为奴隶大军吗 你们该知道......
Coming up next, are you ready to be a slave army? What you need to know.
包起来当是孩子的圣诞礼物吧
And... wrap that up and give it to a child on Christmas,
- 我们收工了 - 好了 明天见 哈尔
- 'cause we're done. - OK. See you tomorrow, Hal.
等等 洛丝 我家正要办个聚会
Wait. Roxie, I'm having a party at my house.
就算是放松一下什么的
It's gonna be, like, off the hook, or whatever.
你应该来玩玩 我找了个DJ
You should come over. I got a deejay,
租了个气垫房子 搞了酒
rented a bouncy house, made a gallon of dip.
很不错的捏
It's gonna be sick.
噢 我...我不知道 哈尔
Oh. I... I don't know, Hal.
我不想去人多的地方
I don't really feel like being around a bunch of people.
不 不 不 那最好了 因为只有你和我
No, no, no, that's the best part. It'll just be like you and me.
嗷 那很吸引人啊
Wow. That... that's certainly very tempting, but...
我还请了个婚礼摄影师
I did hire a wedding photographer. That's just in case we were like,
只是以防我们会做什么疯事
something crazy happened and we wanted a picture of it.
就像是拍一张当纪念 你知道的
Like, maybe we should have this for, like, ever. Like a memory, you know?
我还是不去了
I'm gonna pass.
还有些工作要做 好了 再见
I have some work here that I need to do, anyway.
好吧 周四呢 周四可以考虑不
Cool. So Thursday? Soft Thursday?
- 晚安 哈尔 - 那就是说周四还是可以啦
- Good night, Hal. - That's a soft yes on Thursday.
我是怎么想的? 租了间气垫房子?
What's wrong with me? Rented a bouncy house?
姑娘们都不喜欢气垫房子
Chicks don't like bouncy houses.
他们比较喜欢小丑
They like clowns.
笨蛋车 把我的手都弄破了
Stupid van! You broke my finger!
我铸成了大错
I've made a horrible mistake.
我无心要毁掉你的
I didn't mean to destroy you.
我的意思是 我曾经想要毁掉你
I mean, I meant to destroy you,
但没想到会成功
but I didn't think it would really work.
我们该怎么办?
What are we supposed to do?
没有你 恶魔们在街上会泛滥成灾的
Without you, evil is running rampant through the streets.
我已经厌倦了在大街上捣乱
I'm so tired of running rampant through the streets.
干嘛要做坏人
What's the point of being bad
如果没有好人来阻止你?
when there's no good to try and stop you?
一定要找人去阻止超级大坏蛋
Someone has to stop Megamind.
- 嘿 我们快撞了 - 你吓到我了
- Hey, we're closing soon. - You scared me.
- 巴里 对吗? - 伯纳德
- Barry, right? - Bernard.
伯纳德 刚才我只是... 呃 我在自言自语
Bernard. I was just... Well, I was talking to myself.
你可能认为我有点不对劲
You probably think I'm a little bit nuts.
我不可以直接冒犯客人
I'm not allowed to insult guests directly.
谢谢你 只是... 伯纳德 我想再待一会儿
Thank you. Just... Bernard, I'll just be another minute.
好吧
OK.
谢谢
Thanks.
我还有好多邪恶计划
I had so many evil plans in the works.
傻瓜光线
The illiteracy beam.
台风奶酪
Typhoon cheese.
机械绵羊
Robo- sheep.
后无来者的较量
Battles we will now never have.
我连道别的机会都没有
You know, I never had the chance to say goodbye.
所以只好趁现在了
So it's good that we have this time now.
摧毁这里之前
You know, before I destroy the place.
我对事不对人 只是这地方给我太多痛苦回忆
Nothing personal, it just brings back too many painful memories.
有人吗?
Hello?
- 有人吗? - 是洛克斯安
- Hello? - Roxanne.
- 你的戏服真是俗不可耐 - 戏服?
- That's a pretty tasteless costume. - Costume?
超级大坏蛋的头也没弄得这么夸张
Megamind's head is not that grossly exaggerated.
你居然还做了这么劣质的脱水枪仿制品 多么...
And you even made a cheap replica of his dehydration gun. How...
你好? 有人吗?
Hello? Is someone there?
你好? 谁在那里啊?
Hello? Who's there?
伯纳德 是你啊
It's just you, Bernard.
对啊 只有我一个 伯纳德
Yes. It's just me. Bernard.
好吧 谢谢你让我在这透透气
Well, thank you for letting me stay.
听着 如果我是你的话 我不会停留超过2分钟37秒
Look, I wouldn't stay here for more than two minutes and 37 seconds
我们准备拆墙和天花板
if I were you. We're having the walls and ceiling removed.
哇 听起来是一次大翻新耶
Wow, that sounds like quite the renovation.
那我和你一起下去好了
I guess I'll catch a ride down with you then.
我一直在想他最后关头会想做什么
I kept thinking he was gonna do one of his last- minute escapes.
会吧 他真是个厉害角色
Yeah. He was really good at those.
噢 要是这世上有个重启按钮就好了
Oh, if only the world had a reset button.
我已经研究过这个按钮了
I've looked into the reset button.
科学根本做不到
The science is impossible.
噢 伯纳德...
Oh, Bernard...
我不知道你是...多愁善感 你还好吧?
I didn't know you had... feelings. Are you OK?
曼城卫士已经走了 再也没人可以威胁超级大坏蛋
Metro Man's gone. And now there's no one left to challenge Megamind.
想开点吧 伯纳德
Oh, come on, Bernard.
只要恶魔尚在 正义使者一定会出击的
As long as there's evil, good will rise up against it.
希望如此
Oh, I wish.
我相信总会有人站出来阻止超级大坏蛋
I believe someone is gonna stand up to Megamind.
- 你真的这么想? - 对啊 我的意思是 俗话说
- You really think so? - Yeah. I mean, it's like they say,
时势造英雄
"Heroes aren't born, they're made."
英雄能造出来 对啊!
Heroes can be made. That's it!
你只需要找到对的配件就行啦
All you need are the right ingredients.
- 对 勇敢 - 没错
- Yeah. Bravery. - Yes.
- 力量 - 当然
- Strength. - Of course.
- 决心 - 必需的!
- Determination. - Imperative!
加一点DNA 噢 有了这个 人人都可以做英雄!
And a smidgen of DNA. Oh, with that, anyone can be a hero!
对啊!
Yeah!
我想我们要跑了
I think we should run!
再见!
Bye!
是时候要忘掉过去了
Time to put the past behind us.
只关注未来...
Only the future...
太近喇 我现在真的被吓到了
I'm too close! I'm genuinely scared right now.
希望没被人看到
I hope no one's seeing this!
制造一个英雄? 等一下 什么? 为什么?
Create a hero? Wait, wait, what? Why would you do that?
那我就有对手喇
So I have someone to fight.
小跟班 我是一个没英雄打的坏蛋
Minion, I'm a villain without a hero.
就像阴缺少了阳
A yin with no yang.
斗牛赛没有斗牛
A bullfighter with no bull to fight.
也就是说 我没动力
In other words, I have no purpose.
来 问我打算怎么做 来吧 问啊
Now, ask me how I'm going to do it. Go on! Ask!
你打算怎么做?
How are you gonna do it?
我打算给某个人...还没想好是谁...
I'm going to give someone... I don't know who yet...
曼城卫士的能力
Metro Man's powers.
我要训练这个人变成蛮城的新英雄
I'm going to train that someone to become Metrocity's new hero.
我在这 跟上!
Over here! Follow!
最终 我会和这位英雄决战
And then finally, I'm going to fight that hero
一场史诗般的正邪之战
in an epic battle of good and evil.
一切将和以前一样
Which will put everything back the way it was...
世界还是一样的愉快美好
...when the world was perfect and rosy.
小跟班 看着吧 曼城卫士的斗篷
Behold, Minion, Metro Man's cape.
看清楚了 告诉我你看到什么
Look closely. Tell me what you see.
- 头屑? - 对 就是他的DNA
- Dandruff? - Yes. It's his DNA.
从这里 我们可以找到他的超能力源头
From this, we'll extract the source of Metro Man's awesome power.
主人 我觉得这是个坏主意
Sir, I think this is a bad idea.
对! 这是个超级邪恶的主意 无人能比
Yes! This is a very wickedly bad idea for the greater good of man.
但我意思是这种坏有点不怎么样...
But I'm saying this is a kind of bad that...
好吧 或许在你看来超级邪恶
...OK, you might think is good in your bad perception,
但普通人看来 只是有点坏而已
but from a good perception it... it's just plain bad.
噢 你根本不晓得什么是好坏
Oh, you don't know what's good for bad.
现在 我们只有一次机会
Now, we have just one shot at this.
我们必须找个合适的对象 心地要高贵
We must find a suitable subject, someone of noble heart and mind.
总是无私地替别人着想
Who puts the welfare of others above their own.
到底什么在响啊?
What on Earth is that?
主人 听起来是从那里传出来的
It seems to be emanating from there, sir.
喔罗?
OIIo.
是"哈罗"
It's "Hello."
哈罗? 像这样吗?
Hello? Like that?
- 伯纳德 是我 洛克斯安 - 是洛克斯安
- Bernard, it's Roxanne. - It's Roxanne.
我打来是想谢谢你那天的鼓励
I just wanted to thank you for inspiring me the other day.
- 噢 你也启发了我 - 太好了
- Oh, you inspired me too. - Great!
是时候去阻止超级大坏蛋 告诉他我们不会任凭摆布
It's time we stood up to Megamind and show him he can't push us around.
噢 是吗? 她好可爱
Oh, really? She's so cute.
我对他的下落已经有头绪了
I'm already hot on his trail.
- 什么启发了你啊? - 主人?
- And what gives you that idea? - Sir?
我刚找到他的秘密藏身处
I just found his secret hideout.
她怎么找到我的藏身处? !
How did she find my hideout? !
呃 你怎么找到他的藏身处的?
How did you find his hideout?
这是曼城唯一一栋建筑物屋顶有假天文台
This is the only building in Metro City with a fake observatory on the roof.
算了 她没办法找到秘密入口的
OK. There's no way she'll find the secret entrance.
有张地毯写着"秘密入口"!
There's a doormat here that says "Secrit Entrance"!
- 小跟班! - 我老忘记入口在哪
- Minion! - I kept forgetting where it was.
她会发现我们所有的秘密!
She'll discover all our secrets!
- 噢 不! - 你这个笨科学废品
- Oh, no! - You dim- witted creation of science!
- 什么? - 什么? 不 不 不是你 洛克斯安
- What? - What? Oh, no, not you, Roxanne.
没有 我刚在对我母亲的骨灰瓮...大喊大叫
No, I was just yelling at my... mother's urn.
不要乱来 我很快到
Don't do anything. I'll be right there.
洛克斯安?
Roxanne?
噢 不是吧 又不见了
Oh no, not again!
洛克斯安?
Roxanne?
很高兴你在这 等一下 你怎么这么快就到啊?
I'm glad you're here. Wait, how did you get here so fast?
呃 我...我刚好在这附近竞走
Well, I... I happened to be speed walking nearby when you called.
穿着西装?
In a suit?
这叫..."正式竞走" 那不重要
It's called... formal speed walking, but that's not important.
我来带路吧 这条路看起来比较刺激
I better take the lead. This way looks exciting.
不 那写着"出口"
No, it says "Exit."
也就是刺激的另一种说法 对吧
Which is the abbreviation for "exciting," right?
这里就是喇
This is the mother Iode!
- 哇 快看啊 - 哇
- Wow. Just look at this thing. - Wow.
知道吗 我真的需要你帮忙解开这些秘密
You know, I really could use your help in deciphering all this.
- 真的吗? - 你是专家啊
- Really? - You're an expert
- 很了解超级大坏蛋的一切 对吧? - 对 没错
- on all things Megamind, right? - Yes. Right.
我们共同协力找到他的邪恶计划 并阻止他
Together, we could figure out his plan for the city and stop it.
- 要加入吗? - 噢 太好玩了
- Are you in? - Oh, what fun!
我就想听这句
That's what I want to hear.
小跟班 暗号: 派脑蝇出来
Minion, Code: Send In The Brain- bots.
你知道的 当暗号发出时...
You know, the whole point of a code is...
噢 暗号: 照做就对了 小跟班
Oh, Code: Just Do It, Minion.
入侵者! 入侵者! 入侵者!
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
- 是我啊 你们这群蠢材 - 伯纳德!
- It's me, you fools! - Bernard!
是你爹啊
It's Daddy!
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
- 你把伯纳德怎么样了? - 噢 伯纳德? 对了
- What have you done with Bernard? - Oh, Bernard? Oh, yes.
我正在折磨他
I'm doing horrible things to that man.
我不想伤害他 不过那些镭射光线 钉子
I don't want to get into it, but lasers, spikes.
不 求求你! 不要! 不要用镭射光线 不要用钉子
No, please! No! Not the lasers and the spikes!
- 你知道钻孔器吧 - 噢 不要! 不要钻孔!
- You know the drill. - Oh, no! Not the drill!
- 放他走 不然的话... - 不然什么?
- Let him go or... - Or what?
不然的话我就会知道这把奇形怪状枪的用途
Or I'm gonna find out what this weird- Iooking gun does.
不 别开枪! 别用这把枪!
No, don't shoot! Don't shoot that gun!
我这就去救他
I'll just go get him.
- 放开我 你这恶魔 - 做不到!
- Unhand me, you fiend! - Never!
他的力量太强大了!
His strength's too much!
噢 我做到了!
Oh, I work out!
真的奏效了 你好苗条啊
Well, it's really paying off! You're so fit,
还有着不可思议的魅力
and strangely charismatic.
你没事吧?
Are you OK?
我尽力了 但他太厉害了
I did my best, but he's too fantastic.
给我吧 这么重的枪我帮你拿
Here. Let me carry that heavy gun for you.
我来就好
I got us covered.
- 放手 这是我的枪! - 伯纳德快跑!
- Let go. It's mine! - Bernard, run!
洛克斯安?
Roxanne?
- 快被你弄烂了! - 给我!
- You're going to break it! - Give it to me!
噢 不!
Oh, no!
洛克斯安? !
Roxanne? !
那到底是谁啊?
Who on Earth is that?
- 救命啊! - 洛克斯安!
- Help! - Roxanne!
伯纳德! 你是对的 这门后真够刺激的
Bernard! You were right about that door being exciting.
- 入侵者! 入侵者! - 走这边
- Intruder! Intruder! - This way.
入侵者! 入侵者! 入侵者!
Intruder! Intruder! Intruder!
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
这能阻止它们 拿着!
This'll stop them. Here!
有点太极端了 不是吗?
Seems a bit extreme, doesn't it?
- 快扔啊! - 爹爹我很抱歉
- Just throw it! - Daddy's sorry.
- 哇 真刺激啊 - 对啊
- Wow. That was really exciting. - Yeah.
- 你好强大啊 - 我知道
- You were very strong in there. - I know.
除了曼城卫士 我没见过有人能阻止他
I've never seen anyone but Metro Man stand up to him like that.
- 怎么回事? - 哈尔 发生什么事了?
- What's going on? - Hal, what happened?
我想有只蜜蜂撞到我鼻子了
I think a bee flew up my nose.
我正准备冲进去救你
I was just about to make my frontal assault to rescue you,
但貌似有50个忍者袭击我 所以我必须要先对付他们
but like 50 ninjas tried to attack me, so I had to beat 'em all up,
我搞定了 我...他们全部都哭着求饶...
and I did, and I... They were all, like, crying and stuff...
- 哇 好勇敢啊 对吗? - 你是谁?
- Wow, a brave one, isn't he? - Who are you?
噢 这...这是伯纳德 我的搭档
Oh, thi... this is Bernard. He's my partner.
- 搭档? - 对 对 搭档
- Partner? - Yes. Yes. Partner.
听着 搭档 我才是她的搭档 她只是不晓得自己在说什么
Well, look, "partner," I'm her partner. She doesn't know what she's saying.
她有创伤后遗症
She's been through a traumatic experience.
我想我要带他回家了 再次谢谢你伯纳德
I'd better take him home. Thanks again, Bernard.
搭档 我明天打给你
I'll call you tomorrow, partner.
好啊 没问题 等你电话
Yeah, OK. I'd like that.
真奇怪啊你
That was weird for everybody,
因为你意外地不抱我反而抱他
'cause you accidentally hugged him instead of me.
主人? 主人!
Sir? Sir!
暗号: 你知道那是谁了吗?
Code: Did You Find Out who It was?
暗号: 把车开过来
Code: Get The Car.
暗号: 马上到 主人
Code: Right Away, Sir.
- 再见! - 明天见 哈尔
- Bye- bye! - See you tomorrow, Hal.
我不会锁门 免得你晚点想来看我
I'll leave the door unlocked in case you want to check on me later.
这男的是谁啊? 我们已经被注入神力了
Who is this man we've infused with godlike power?
主人 他叫哈尔 斯图尔特 28岁
Well, sir, his name's Hal Stewart. He's 28 years old.
没有犯罪前科 事实上完全没记录
No criminal record. Actually no records at all.
很明显这个男人一事无成
Apparently this man hasn't accomplished anything.
小跟班 还没而已 还没...而已
Not yet, Minion. Not... yet.
难道日子不能变得有趣一点吗?
Could this day get anymore fun- tastic?
所以我要过去射毁他的力量 因为这根本就是个错误
So, I will just go ahead and diffuse him since this is clearly a mistake.
不 小跟班 这活儿远没那么简单
No, Minion! There's something much more powerful at work here.
这不是错误 这是命中注定的
This is no mistake. It's destiny.
哈尔 斯拖尔特! 准备迎接你的命运吧!
Hal Shtewart! Prepare for your destiny!
哈尔? 哈尔 斯拖尔特?
Hal? Hal Shtewart?
- 嘿 在床上! - 我说得对吗?
- Hey! In the bed! - Am I saying it right?
念"斯图尔特"才对
"Stewart."
想打劫吗?
Is this a robbery?
因为对面的女士拥有更多值钱东西
'Cause the lady across the hall has way better stuff than me.
噢 看啊 是哈尔 斯图尔特 快啊 喷一下
Oh, look, it's Hal Stewart. Quick, the spray.
用光了
All out.
- 那就用失忆棒吧 - 噢 对啊
- Well, use the Forget- Me Stick. - Oh, right.
看着他
Just look at him.
不 他完全不像个英雄的样子
No, he doesn't look quite the hero- type to me.
小跟班 你真是个讨厌鬼
Oh, you're such a pill, Minion.
无论资质好坏 都可以做英雄
A potter couldn't ask for finer clay.
我闻到英雄的气息
I smell a hero.
我闻到有东西糊了
I smell something burning.
起作用喇! 各就各位!
I think it's working. Places! Places!
准备好 各就各位
Places! Places! Places.
你准备好伪装了吗?
Do you have your disguise?
什么啊?
What?
噢 你看上去太美了
Oh, you look fantastic.
醒来吧 我最伟大的创造
Rise my glorious creation.
醒来吧 到爹爹这里来
Rise, and come to Papa.
- 发生什么了? - 别紧张 孩子
- What's going on? - Easy my child.
- 你是谁? - 是我把你送到这个星球来的
- Who are you? - I sent you to this planet
教会你正义 荣耀 和高尚
to teach you about justice, honor, and nobility.
我是你父亲
I am your father.
你是我的宇宙父亲?
So you're like my space dad?
对 我是你的宇宙父亲
Yeah, I'm like your space dad.
那你是?
And you are what?
我是你的宇宙继母
I'm your space stepmom.
我最近整形了
I've had some work done recently.
这是梦吗?
Is this some kind of dream?
是梦想成真
This is a dream come true.
你已经被赐予深不可测的能力
You've been blessed with unfathomable power.
- 什么能力 - 深不可测
- What kind of power? - Unfathomable.
就是深...得无法了解
It's unf... without fathom.
对 我们来指导你
Yeah. We've come to guide you
成为蛮城的新英雄
on your path to be Metrocity's new hero
与超天才超级大坏蛋决战
and battle the super- genius of Megamind.
我知道你一时无法接受这么多
I know this is a lot to take in.
这也许需要几个月时间来理解
It may take months for you to come to grips.
开什么玩笑!
No freaking way!
我还没说完
I wasn't finished.
我要当英雄!
I'm gonna be a hero!
我要当英雄喇!
看吧 小跟班 他是完美的
See, Minion, he's perfect!
开始!
And... action!
- 帮帮我! - 我没事!
- Someone help me! - I'm OK!
你这个...坏蛋!
You... Bad!
杀! 杀! 杀!
Zap! Zap! Zap!
燃烧恶魔的火焰光亮无比
The flames of my evil burn bright.
现在你来说些什么报复我吧
Now you say something cool back at me.
看 完全不会痛 感觉不到什么
Look. It doesn't even hurt. Don't even feel it.
不不不 不是 肚子往下 手往上 像个曼城卫士
No, no, no, no, no. Stomach down, hands up. Like Metro Man.
- 哇 等一下! - 小心
- Whoa! Wait! - Watch out.
他没救了 没救了!
He's hopeless. Hopeless!
- 或许我们可以改变策略 - 真的吗?
- Maybe we should change tactics. - You think so?
噢 你知道男孩的
Oh, you know how boys are.
他们喜欢电脑游戏
They love video games.
- 我可以找几个玩伴 - 等不及了
- I could throw a few parts together. - Can't wait.
大声地笑 笑脸
LOL. Smiley face.
等不及什么 主人?
Can't wait for what, sir?
真是个有趣的故事
That was such a funny story.
顺便说一句 说得很精彩
And brilliantly told, by the way.
好了 轮到你说一个
OK, now you tell one.
伯纳德我从不知道你这么风趣
Bernard, I never knew you were so funny.
我也从没听过你笑
And I never heard you laugh before.
对啊 好一阵子了 感觉很好啊
Yeah, it's been a while. Feels pretty good.
开始
And action.
搞定你喇!
Gotcha!
- 你不常出外的 对吗? - 噢 多好玩啊
- You don't get out much, do you? - Oh, what fun!
我小时候和我妈来过这里
I used to come here with my mother when I was a kid.
是我最爱做的事情之一
It was one of my favorite things to do.
现在看来 是个垃圾堆
Now look at it. It's a dump.
为什么我们要打扫城市啊 主人?
Why are we cleaning up the city, sir?
我们不希望咱们的新英雄在垃圾堆里战斗吧?
Well, we don't want to battle our new hero in a dump now, do we?
他们都回来了 可是怎么会? 为什么?
They're all back. But how? Why?
或许超级大坏蛋没有那么坏呢
Maybe Megamind isn't so bad after all.
就是这样喇
That's it.
飞吧 像鸽子般飞翔吧
Be free, my beautiful dove!
好吧 好吧
OK, OK.
曼城卫士和我从来都没有在一起
Metro Man and I were never a couple.
- 可我还以为你们俩... - 我知道 所有人都这么想
- But I thought you two were... - I know. Everybody did.
只是...他不是我喜欢的类型
It's just... Well, he was never really my type.
真的?
Really?
好了 轮到你告诉我
OK, now you tell me something.
一些你从没告诉别人的秘密
Something you've never told anyone.
呃 在学...学校...
Well, in sh... school...
没有人喜欢过我
...none of the other kids really liked me.
我从来就是被剩下的那个
I was always the last one picked for everything.
我没和你在同一间学校太遗憾了
It's too bad that we didn't go to the same school.
哈尔 我想你已经准备好了
Hal, I think you're ready for this.
- 我有儿子了? - 没有
- Do I have a son? - No.
你真幽默
You make me laugh.
它可以伸展的 给你穿的
It stretches. It's for you.
这个字母T是什么意思?
Hey, what's the T stand for?
太阳神
Titan.
"太阳神"? 什么意思?
"Titan"? What's that supposed to mean?
只有这个名字可以注册成商标了
It was the only name I could trademark.
哈尔 在你生命里 有特别的人吗?
Do you have someone special in your life, Hal?
还没有 不过...有一个很漂亮的女孩
No, not yet. But... there's this really, really good- Iooking one
我的眼睛总离不开她
I've got my eye on currently.
那很好
That's very good.
- 恋情是很鼓舞人的 - 我也是这么认为的
- Romance is very inspiring. - That's what I hear.
你要做的是拯救她 那么她就是你的了
All you have to do is save her and she'll be yours.
- 我想要炸油条? - 我!
- Who wants churros? - I do!
- 我要 谢谢你 宇宙继母 - 炸油条一直陪伴你
- I do, yeah. Thanks, Space Stepmom. - Churros all the way around.
数到三 拔出油条
On the count of three, unsheathe your churro.
一二三!
One, two, three!
敬太阳神!
To Titan!
明天 你会和超级大坏蛋决斗 整个城市将会知道你的名字
Tomorrow, you will fight Megamind, and the city will know your name.
城市的公园恢复往日的风采
...the city's parks restored to their original glory,
街道治安稳定 银行重新开张
the streets the safest they've been, the banks reopened.
超级大坏蛋发生什么了吗?
Has something happened to Megamind?
难道有人降服了这只怪兽?
Has someone tamed this monster?
这是洛克斯安 瑞驰 谨慎乐观
This is Roxanne Ritchi, cautiously optimistic,
愉悦困扰地为你报导
and pleasantly confused.
今晚你看起来心情不错啊 主人
Well, you seem in a very good mood tonight, sir.
对啊 小跟班 还要多长时间啊?
Oh, yes. How long is this going to take, Minion?
只剩一点点修改了 主人 很快做好
Just a few alterations, sir, and I will be done
你的最可怕斗篷
with your most terrifying cape yet!
我要把它命名为...
I'm calling it...
黑曼巴蛇!
...the Black Mamba...
黑曼巴蛇 很好
Black Mamba. Perfect.
天啊 我快迟到了 我要走了
Gosh, I am running late. I have to go.
什么? 哪...你要去哪里 主人?
What? Where... Where are you going, sir?
明天早上我们和太阳神初次登场战斗
We have our debut battle with Titan tomorrow morning.
我们还没测试过你的大战斗服呢
We haven't even tested your big battle suit yet.
小跟班 你处理好细节先 我要...帮人跑腿办件事
You attend to the details, Minion. I have to... run a quick errand.
你不会帮人跑腿的
You don't run errands.
- 发生什么了? - 什么?
- What's going on here? - What?
噢 等一下
Oh, wait a minute.
你擦了名牌香水?
Are you wearing Jean Paul Gaultier's Pour Homme?
只是我的体香而已 车钥匙在哪?
It's just my natural musk. Now, where are the car keys?
和瑞驰小姐有关 对不对?
This is about Ms. Ritchi, isn't it?
你在和她约会
You're going on a date with her.
不是 兄弟 别闹了
No, my main man. Get out of town.
噢 糟了 糟了 你爱上她了
Oh, this is bad. This is bad. You've fallen in love with her.
小跟班 你太多管闲事了 把钥匙给我
You are forgetting your place, Minion. Now give me the keys.
如果洛克斯安发现你是谁 那怎么办?
What happens when Roxanne finds out who you really are?
她不会发现的 不然我干嘛还撒谎?
She will never find out. That's the point of lying.
老实说 如果我不认识你
Honestly, if I didn't know any better,
我会以为你第一天来当恶魔
I'd think this was your first day of being evil.
不!
No!
这太过分了喔
This has gone far enough!
噢 你翅膀硬了啊
Oh, that was really grown- up!
主人 主人 求求你 这是为你好
Sir, sir, please. It's for your own good.
噢 你知道什么
Oh, what do you know?
我或许不知道太多 但我知道:
I may not know much, but I do know this:
坏人是得不到心爱的女人的
The bad guy doesn't get the girl.
或许我再也不想当坏人了
Maybe I don't want to be the bad guy anymore.
你听到了
You heard me!
你是谁啊?
Who are you?
- 快把钥匙给我! - 不给!
- Now, give me the keys! - No!
我生来就是要照顾你
My sole purpose in life is to look after you.
我不需要你的照顾
Well, I don't need you to look after me.
你说什...你说什么? 你不需要我?
What are you s... What are you saying? You don't need me?
让我把话说清楚 暗号: 我不需要你
Let me make it clear. Code: I Don't Need You.
你知道吗? 你知道吗?
You know what? You know what?
暗号: 我会收拾行李 然后离开!
Code: I'll Just Pack My Thing And Go!
- 暗号: 随便你! - 暗号: 我也随便你!
- Code: Fine! - Code: Fine Back!
- 祝你约会顺利 - 我会的
- Well, good luck on your date! - I will!
- 这完全说不过去 - 我知道
- That doesn't even make any sense! - I know!
我快接近真相了 我可以感觉到它
I know I am so close. I can feel it.
好吧 好吧 我得回想一下
OK, OK. I just have to take a step back.
等一下
Wait a minute.
太阳神
"Titan."
- 太阳神是什么东西? - 我的顺风耳听到东西喇
- What's a Titan? - My super- ears are burning.
我通常只听到罪犯的声音 你没有捣乱吧?
I usually just hear criminals. You haven't been naughty, have you?
我在开玩笑 我在开玩笑
I'm totally messing with you. I'm totally messing with you.
- 我叫太阳神 - 太阳神
- The name's Titan. - Titan.
正直可敬的英雄守护者
Your very own heroic guardian of pure awesome.
你叫什么名字? 我开玩笑的 我知道你的一切
What's your name? Just kidding. I know everything about you.
我...我带了花来
And I... And I brought some flowers.
不知道你喜欢什么 所以我全部都带来的
Didn't know what you liked, so I just grabbed, you know, all of them.
好吧 不喜欢花? 算了 忽略这些花
OK. You don't like flowers? OK, forget the flowers.
你想干嘛?
What do you want?
或许我们可以一起去兜风 飞遍整个城市
Thought maybe we could go for a little flight around town.
先互相了解一下
Get to know each other first.
一定会让你很兴奋的
This must be very thrilling for you.
你知道你在干嘛吗?
What do you think you're doing? !
噢 我飞太快了吗? 你是对的
Oh, am I moving too fast? You're probably right.
我应该先拯救你几次 再进行浪漫桥段的
I should just rescue you a few times before we get all romantic.
救到你喇
Saved ya.
有我这个伟大的英雄 你真够幸运的
You are lucky to have such a great hero here.
- 你居然敢... - 噢 糟了 赶快找人来救她
- Don't you ever... - Oh, no! Somebody do something!
噢 对了 对了 我来喇 我来喇
Oh, right, right, duh. I gotcha. I gotcha.
好刺激啊 你差点没命了
That was a close one. You almost died,
- 但我救了你 - 大楼!
- but I saved you. - Building!
接住你了 不好意思 你刚刚说什么
Gotcha! I'm sorry. What were you saying?
我救你的声音太大 听不见
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me saving your life.
放我下来 马上
Put me down! Right now!
好 知道了 知道了 等一下
OK, all right. All right, hold on.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我想我是有点 有点为你而疯
I suppose I'm a, I'm a little crazy, about you.
你到底是谁
Who are you, really?
好了 准备好大吃一惊吧 小姐
Oh, right. Well, prepare to have your mind blown, little lady.
- 当当 - 哈尔?
- Ta- da. - Hal?
正是 是不是很棒 现在没什么能分开我们了
Yeah. Isn't this great? Now there's nothing keeping us apart.
- 不 一点都不棒 - 哇 这可是我们的第一次吵架
- No. It's not great. - Wow. Our first fight.
太有我俩的特色了 我们就像一对老夫妻一样
This is so us. We're like an old married couple.
听着 根本没有"我们"这个说法 永远都不会有
Look, there is no "us," OK? There will never be an "us."
可是...我有超能力啊
But... I have powers.
我有个斗篷 我是个好人
I have a cape. I'm the good guy.
你是个好人 哈尔 可是你不明白
You are a good guy, Hal, but you don't understand.
- 我们得搞清楚为什么... - 不 不 这...
- We need to find out why... - No, no. This...
- 哈尔 深呼吸 - 不该是这样的
- Hal, just take a deep breath - This isn't right!
- 听我说 - 你应该和我在一起
- And listen to me for a moment. - You're supposed to be with me!
我警告你 哈尔
I'm trying to warn you, Hal.
叫我太阳神 叫太阳神 不要叫我哈尔
It's Titan! It's Titan, not Hal!
- 伯纳德 - 洛克斯安
- Bernard. - Roxanne.
- 对不起 我来晚了 - 哇 你的头发看起来受了点刺激啊
- Sorry I'm late. - Wow, your hair looks exciting.
今天晚上刺激的可不止这点
Not the only exciting development of the night.
超级大坏蛋造出来一个新的英雄 我知道他为什么这么做
Megamind's created a new hero, and I know why.
现在都说得通了 他怀念有人教训他的日子
It all makes sense now. He missed getting his butt kicked,
所以就造出来一个新的英雄
so he created a new hero
- 好有人教训他 - 正是
- to kick it for him. - Yeah.
可是为什么他选上了哈尔
But why would he pick Hal?
哈尔是最糟糕的选择了
Hal is the worst possible person you could pick.
哇 真是让人难以接受啊
Wow. That's a lot to take in.
这太难以置信了
It boggles my mind.
太让我难以接受了 不过 我确信
I am extremely boggled. You know, I'm sure we'll get
我们总会弄清楚是谁教训谁的
to the bottom of who's kicking whose butt.
可是现在呢 我们还是 好好享受我们的时光吧
But in the meantime, let's enjoy each other's company.
抱歉 伯纳德 你是对的
I'm sorry, Bernard, of course, you're right.
我应该闭嘴了
You know, I could use a breather.
敬伯纳德
To Bernard,
你是我这疯狂的 乱七八糟的世界里 唯一正常的存在
for being the only normal thing in my crazy, upside- down world.
为正常 干杯
To... being normal.
- 洛克斯安 - 嗯?
- Roxanne? - Yes?
如果我不那么正常
Say I wasn't so normal.
如果我这人秃头 而且肤色跟常人不太一样
Let's say I was bald and had the complexion of,
我只是说如果 并不特指谁
of a popular primary color, as a random, nonspecific example.
- 你还会愿意和我做朋友吗 - 那当然
- Would you still enjoy my company? - Of course!
不能以貌取人嘛
You don't judge a book by its cover or a person from the outside.
听你这么说我放心了
That's a relief to hear.
看一个人应该看他的言行才是
You judge them based on their actions.
这无足挂齿 是吧
Well, that seems kind of petty, don't you think?
怎么了 怎么了
What? What?
不要看我 出了点技术故障
Don't look at me! Just a technical glitch!
现在别看 不要介意
Don't look yet! Well, never mind that.
好了
OK.
我们说到哪里了
Where were we?
- 是你... - 镇定 镇定
- You... - Now, now, hold on.
是你
You!
我可以解释的
I can explain!
你刚刚说的还算数吗?
What about everything you just said?
你说过不以貌取人的
About judging a book by its cover?
好 那我们来说说内涵
Well, let's take a look at the contents then, shall we?
你毁了曼城卫士 接管了这城市
You destroyed Metro Man, you took over the city,
你让我在乎你
and then, you actually got me to care about you!
你为什么这么坏 耍我
Why are you so evil? Tricking me?
对你有什么好处
What could you possibly hope to gain?
等等 我不信
Wait a minute. I don't believe this.
你不会真的以为我会和你在一起吧
Do you really think that I would ever be with you?
是啊
No.
小跟班 你说的对
OK, Minion! You were right!
我...不完全对
I was... less right!
我们应该坚持我们擅长的 做坏人
We should stick to what we're good at... being bad.
小跟班
Minion?
你
You there!
对 就是你
Yeah, you.
把黑曼巴蛇拿出来
Bring out the Black Mamba.
好了 太阳神 咱就是堕落也要有范
OK, Titan. It's time to go down in style.
我听说新出现了一个英雄 敢挑战我
I hear there's a new hero who dares challenge my evil.
那个叫太阳神的在哪
Where is the one they call Titan?
你有胆就来挑战我
Challenge me if you dare!
哦 不 我们要撞车了
Oh no. We're gonna crash!
这也太尴尬了
This is embarrassing.
整个就是欠考虑 没技术含量
Of all the inconsiderate, bone- headed...
...不负责任 鲁莽...
...irresponsible, rude...
这就叫不专业
Unprofessional, that's what this is!
如果是曼城卫士会让我等这么久吗
Would Metro Man have kept me waiting?
当然不会 他可是够专业的
Of course not! He was a pro!
嘿 超级大坏蛋 我正想见你呢
Hey, Megamind! You're actually the guy I want to see.
门在那
Also, there's a door here.
你知道我等了你多久吗
Do you have any idea how long I waited for you?
不不不 我不明白你在说什么
No, no, no, I totally understand what you're saying.
你能不能安静一会 我正在打这关
Could you just, just shut up for one second. I'm trying to beat this level.
你到底有想过要出场吗
Were you even planning on showing up?
这是什么
What's this?
你从哪弄来的这些
Where did you get all this stuff?
这不是我的
It doesn't belong to me.
- 你偷的? - 帅吧?
- You stole it? - Pretty cool, right?
- 不不不 你是个英雄 - 当英雄是窝囊废干的事
- No, no, no, no! You're a hero! - Being a hero is for losers!
工作工作工作 一天24小时 一周7天 这有什么意义
It's work, work, work, 24/7, and for what?
我演这出就是为了得到那女孩
I only took the gig to get the girl,
结果发现洛克斯安什么都不愿意跟我一起做
and it turns out Roxanne doesn't want anything to do with me.
- 洛克斯安 瑞驰? - 正是 洛克斯安 瑞驰!
- Roxanne Ritchi? - Yeah! Roxanne Ritchi!
我看见她跟人吃晚餐
I saw her having dinner and making googly eyes
还对着那个傻乎乎的书呆子 把眼睛瞪得溜圆!
at some intellectual dweeb!
谁稀罕这些玩意啊
Who needs all that noise?
所以我觉得我俩应该合作
That's why I think we should team up.
你 等等 你说什么
You... Wait... What?
我的力量 加上你的聪明
With my power, and your big- headedness,
- 我们就可以统治这个城市 - 你想合作?
- we could rule the city! - You want to team up?
我还设计了我俩的行头
I even drew up some new costume designs, see?
- 设计行头? - 你负责出谋划策
- Costume designs? - You'd be the brains,
所以你的标志就是个大脑
so you'd get a little brain,
再戴上个墨镜什么的
wearing glasses on your costume, or something.
而我就是那个主角 我就要
And since I'm the cool one, I'd have, like,
两个击剑的坦克...
two tanks swordfighting...
我没办法相信
I can't believe you.
你的天赋 你的力量
All your gifts, all your powers,
而你却把它们挥霍在浪费自己的私欲上
and you... you squander them for your own personal gain.
- 对 - 不 我才是唱白脸的
- Yes! - No! I'm the villain!
你是唱红脸的 我来做坏事
You're the good guy! I do something bad,
你来抓我 我造你的原因就是这个
and you come and get me! That's why I created you.
对 对 你疯了 宇宙老爸告诉我...
Yeah, right. You're nuts. Space Dad told me...
看 我就是你的宇宙老爸
Look, I'm your space dad!
你应该更像曼城卫士
You should be more like Metro Man.
- 你骗我 - 哦 你不喜欢那样?
- You tricked me? - Oh, don't like that?
还有呢
Well, there's more.
我还是跟洛克斯安拍拖的那个书呆子
I'm also the intellectual dweeb dating Roxanne.
- 不 - 而且我俩进展神速
- No. - And we were smooching up a storm!
你被我抓到 我就
When I get my hands on you, I'm gonna...
对 对 我知道 伸张正义吧
Yes! Yes, I know! Bring me to justice.
哦 神啊 我可怀念这样了
Oh God, how I've missed this.
英雄重重地打出了他的第一拳
And the hero strikes the first blow.
而坏人马上反击
But evil returns with a backhand!
耶
Yes!
出来 你个小怪物!
Come out, you little freak!
我要看看你那大头放在人行道上是什么效果
I want to see what that big brain looks like on the pavement!
最老套的把戏就把你给打败了
You fell for the oldest evil trick in the book!
你个蓝不啦叽的笨蛋
You little blue twerp!
预备
En garde!
哦 要的就是这精神!
Oh, now that's the spirit!
我挡! 我刺! 我再挡!
Parry! Thrust! Parry again!
现在 计谋放一边 该是把戏上场了
Now it's time for some witty back and forth banter!
你先
You go first!
好了 我不知道怎么办才好了
OK! Look, I'm not sure where to go with that!
这一招是为了你偷走我女朋友
This one's for stealing my girlfriend!
这一招是为了你装宇宙老爸耍我
This one's for Space Dad making a fool out of me!
还有 超级大坏蛋 还有这一招是为了宇宙继母! 你骗了她
And, Megamind, this one's for Space Stepmom! You lied to her!
干的好 这场架打得很好 很好
Well done. I thought that battle went really, really well.
- 不过 我还想评论几句 - 评论?
- I mean, I have a few notes. - Notes?
这不重要 你可以把我扔进监狱了
But they can wait. You can take me to jail now.
不不不 我想的是太平间 你死定了
Oh, no, no, no. I was thinking more like the morgue. You're dead!
喂喂喂喂喂 游戏可不是这么玩的
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. This isn't how you play the game.
游戏结束了
Game over.
脑蝇!
Brain- bots!
我要求暂停
I'm calling time out!
暂停 暂停 暂停
Time out? Time out! Time out!
脑蝇 启动自动防故障装置
Brain- bots, initiate the fail- safe.
你猜怎么着 这个棕色的家伙 是铜做的
Guess what, Buster Brown? It's made from copper.
这个你可束手无策
You're powerless against it.
我就是用这个来打败... 曼城卫士
It's the very same metal used to defeat... Metro Man?
不要再拿我和曼城卫士比较了
You should stop comparing me to Metro Man!
你可以逃跑 超级大坏蛋 可你躲不掉的
You can run, Megamind, but you can't hide!
我们得救了 我们得救了
We're saved! We're saved!
你叫什么名字 新的英雄?
What's your name, new hero?
- 我叫太阳神 - 谢谢你
- It's Titan. - Thank you!
谢谢你 太阳神解放了我们
Thank you! Titan has freed us!
哦 我可不会说"解放" 应该说是新的统治
Oh, I wouldn't say "free." More like under new management.
- 你想要什么? - 太阳神变坏了
- What do you want? - Titan's turned evil.
恭喜你 你的天才计划又背后捅了你一刀
Congratulations. Another one of your genius plans has backfired on you.
守门的怎么会让你上来的
And why did my doorman let you up?
卡洛斯
Carlos.
求你了 洛克斯安 别关门 别 我要你帮我
Please, Roxanne, no. No. I need your help.
你怎么会需要我帮你
Why do you need my help?
因为你是我认识的最聪明的人
Because you're the smartest person I know.
可你不能躲在这里
But you can't hide here.
铜应该有效的 铜怎么会没用
The copper should have worked. Why didn't the copper work?
上次铜就很有用啊
The copper worked perfectly well last time.
铜 你根本是在胡说八道
Copper? You're not making any sense.
听着 如果我们找不到太阳神的弱点
Look, if we don't find Titan's weakness,
他会把整个城市都毁了
he'll destroy the whole city.
- 好吧 有什么我能帮得上的 - 我们要找到答案
- OK, how can I help? - We need to find answers.
你最了解曼城卫士 他有没有什么藏身处 洞穴之类的?
You knew Metro Man best. Did he have a hideout? A cave?
一个偏远的堡垒什么的 随便什么能给我们线索的东西
A solitary fortress of some kind? Anything that would give us clues.
嗯 我是知道一个地方
Well... there is one place I know.
是你赋予他力量的 你就不能再拿走吗
You gave him these powers. Can't you just take them away?
不能 那天我放错隐形车 丢了镭射枪
I can't. I lost my diffuser gun when I misplaced the invisible car.
就是你甩了我的那天 一个人 还下着雨
The night you dumped me. Alone. In the rain.
你有没有回头过
Did you ever look back?
- 没有 - 我蓝色的大脑袋啊
- No! - My giant blue head!
我想我们到了
I guess we're here.
他就是把它藏在这里的
So, this is where he hid it.
过了这么多年了 我当年的校舍啊
After all these years. My old shoolhouse.
我为了那天晚上的事道歉
You know, I think there's an apology in order for the other night.
那太好了 不过快点
OK, that would be nice, but make it quick.
我们还得对付很多麻烦事呢
We have much more pressing matters to deal with.
哇 我没办法相信这些东西他都留着
Wow. I can't believe he kept all this stuff.
我还记得他穿着这些东西
I remember when he wore that.
- 我们是不是应该专心? - 是 当然的 要专心
- Shouldn't we try to stay focused here? - Yes, of course. Right. Focused.
嘿 过来看看这个
Hey. Come over and look at this.
是什么 你发现什么了
What is it? What did you find?
看
Look.
这杯子里面有冰块
This glass has ice cubes in it.
是啊 水冻了就会变成冰嘛
Yes, that's what happens when water gets cold.
我 我的意思是 你不觉得奇怪吗
No, what I'm saying is, don't you think it's a little odd
这冰居然还没化
that the ice hasn't melted yet?
生命的奥秘
One of life's great mysteries.
嘿
Hey.
我们已经证实了传言
We now have confirmed reports.
太阳神本来以为他是这城市的英雄 现在变坏了
Titan, first thought to be this city's new hero, has turned evil.
这城市从未经历如此的破坏
The city has never seen this level of destruction.
万一曼城卫士还活着
If only Metro Man were still alive.
- 你还活着 - 你还活着
- You're alive? - You're alive.
- 我还活着 - 可是我 我们
- I'm alive. - But I, we...
我们看到你的白骨了 你死了
We saw your skeleton! You were dead!
你是鬼吗
Are you a ghost?
你最好能给我们一个好一点的解释
There had better be an amazing explanation for this.
说话吧 幽灵
Speak, apparition.
好了 好了 好了 好了
OK. OK, OK, OK.
你们都应该知道真相
You both deserve the truth.
一切都从观象台说起
It all started back at the observatory.
洛克斯安被绑架 我应该去解救她
Roxanne was kidnapped. I was gonna stop you.
那天我脑子不太对劲
My head wasn't in the game that day.
我那天就是应付事
We were kind of going through the motions.
于是呢 我就利用我的速度
So... using my super- speed,
我决定去安静安静
I decided to go clear my head.
开炮!
Fire!
然后我意识到
Then I realized,
我们一生都在玩这个傻乎乎的把戏
we had done this same silly charade our entire lives.
我想去忽略我的感觉
I tried to get my mind off how I was feeling,
可心里就是堵得慌
but I just felt stuck.
我忽然明白 除了我的超能力
I began to realize, despite all my powers,
曼城每个市民都有个我所没有的东西 选择的权利
each and every citizen of Metro had something I didn't: A choice.
从我记事起 我只能成为这个城市所希望我去做的
Ever since I can remember, I've always had to be what the city wanted me to be.
我想做的事情呢
But what about what I wanted to do?
这想法忽然出现在我脑海里
Then it suddenly hit me.
我是有选择的
I do have a choice.
我可以做我想做的
I can be whatever I want to be.
没人说过当英雄得是终身的
No one said this hero thing had to be a lifetime gig.
可我也不能就那么退出
You can't just quit, either.
于是 我就想到了这个绝妙的办法 假死
That's when I got the brilliant idea... to fake my death.
铜会消耗我的能量
Copper drains my powers.
你的弱点是铜?
Your weakness is copper?
被你的死亡光波击中的那一霎那 我觉得自己前所未有地活着
Once your death ray hit, I'd never felt so alive.
我就从附近的护士学校借了个道具
So I borrowed a prop from a nearby nursing school.
曼城卫士终于死了
Metro Man was finally dead.
而音乐卫士诞生了
And Music Man was born!
- 音乐卫士? - 这样我就能留着我的标志了
- Music Man? - That way I could keep my logo.
- 为什么? - 又来?
- 'Cause of wha...? - Come again?
我终于能接触我真正的能力...
I was finally free to get in touch with my true power...
...将魔力赋予歌词
...weaving lyrical magic.
听着
Check this out.
我有一双眼睛
I have eyes that can see
能穿透...
Right through lead...
- 你太糟糕了! - 确实 你蛮有天赋
- You're horrible! - Granted, you have talent.
可外面有个疯子 正毁了我们的... 你的城市
But there's a madman out there destroying our... your city.
你怎么可以这样
How could you do this? !
这个城市的市民那么相信你 你却抛弃了他们
The people of this city relied on you, and you deserted them!
你害我们落入他的魔爪
You left us in the hands of him!
- 无意冒犯 - 不 我和你站一边的
- No offense. - No, I'm with you.
我们需要你的帮助
Look, we need your help.
我很抱歉 我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I really am.
我不干了
I'm done.
小兄弟 你知道吗 有阳必有阴
You know, little buddy, there's a yin for every yang.
有邪恶势力 正义势力就会奋起反抗
If there's bad, good will rise up against it.
我花了很多时间才找到我自己的称号
It's taken me a long time to find my calling.
现在是时候去找你自己的称号了
Now it's about time you find yours.
嘿 谁需要他了
Hey, who needs him?
我们自己就可以打败太阳神
We can beat Titan ourselves.
我们可以回到邪恶老巢 带上些镭射枪
I say we go back to the evil lair, grab some ray guns,
把他带到小巷里 叫上所有的黑帮往他身上招呼
hold him sideways, and just go all gangsta on him.
我们不能
We can't.
难道就这样了? 你就这么放弃了?
So that's it? You're just giving up?
我才是坏人 我不会拯救世界 然后飞向夕阳
I'm the bad guy. I don't save the day, I don't fly off into the sunset,
抱得美人归的也不是我
and I don't get the girl.
我要回家
I'm going home.
除非马上有救星降临 否则一切都要毁了
Unless someone comes to our aid soon, all may be lost.
成千上万人涌入城市 上演出埃及记
Thousands have already fled the city in a mass exodus.
而留下的市民们 要记得在另行通知之前不要出门
Remaining citizens are warned to stay indoors until further notice.
当局已发出警告
Authorities have issued a warning
无论如何都要待在市中心
to stay out of the downtown area at all costs.
哈尔!
Hal!
我猜猜 见识过我的厉害后
Let me guess. After seeing how awesome I am,
你终于清醒了 好吧 我忘记你了
you've finally come to your senses? Well, I'm over you.
- 我是来阻止你的 哈尔 - 就你? 好啊
- I've come to stop you, Hal. - You? Oh, wow.
那你打算怎么做? 把我报道死?
OK, what are you gonna do, report me to death?
我要跟你讲道理
I was going to try reasoning with you.
我们两个共事这么久 我了解你
You and I, we worked together for a long time. I know you.
你不了解我 你从来不肯了解我
You don't know me. You never took the time to know me.
这是我俩第一次正式约会
This is the first time we've hung out socially,
也正是我要毁了这城市的时候
and it's when I'm about to destroy the city!
我要跟真正的哈尔说话
I want to talk to the real Hal.
那个热爱摄影师职业的
I want to talk to the guy who loved being a cameraman,
有点耳背 有点呆呆的
and eating dip, and being a nerd,
而且不像太阳神 哈尔的那个人
and being not as scary as the Tighten Hal.
已经晚了
Too late!
...打断了我们的计划...
...interrupting our scheduled...
...发生极端的事件...
...extraordinary events taking place...
打中了山谷...
Heat in the valley and...
超级大坏蛋!
Megamind!
我俩有事没完
You and I have some unfinished business.
我在曼城之塔等你
I'll be waiting at Metro Tower.
还有 为了防止你打退堂鼓...
Oh, and just so you don't get cold feet...
洛克斯安
Roxanne.
来吧 洛丝 呼唤你的英雄 让他来救你
Come on, Roxie, call for your hero to come rescue you.
超级大坏蛋 我不知道你有没有在听 如果你听到了
Megamind, I don't even know if you're listening, but if you are,
你不能放弃
you can't give up.
我所认识的超级大坏蛋可不会逃避
The Megamind I knew would never have run from a fight,
哪怕他知道他绝对没有赢的机会
even when he knew he had absolutely no chance of winning.
这是你最美好的品质
It was your best quality.
你要赶紧振作起来
You need to be that guy right now.
这城市需要你
The city needs you.
我需要你
I need you.
洛克斯安
Roxanne.
给你一个小时
You have one hour.
不要让我等太久
Don't keep me waiting.
典狱官 典狱官 听着 你得放我走
Warden! Warden! Listen to me! You have to let me go!
必须有人阻止太阳神
Tighten has to be stopped!
抱歉了超级大坏蛋 你还有88个无期徒刑要服
Sorry, Megamind. You still have 88 life sentences to go.
够你反省的了
Plenty of time to reflect on what you've done.
你真的要我说吗? 那我说好了
Did you want to hear me say it? I'll say it.
听着 我从我心里最黑暗的地方说
Here it is, from the blackest part of my heart.
对不起
I am sorry!
我可不买帐
Not buying it.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我吓到这城市那么多次
I've terrorized this city countless times.
还造出来一个其实是坏人的英雄
Created a hero who's turned out to be a villain.
我还骗了洛克斯安 还有
I lied to Roxanne, and...
...我最好的朋友小跟班 视他如草芥
...my best friend Minion, I treated like dirt.
请你不要让这个城市...
Please don't make this city...
...不要让洛克斯安 替我受罪
...don't make Roxanne pay for my wrongdoings.
接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
哦 小跟班 你个神奇的小鱼
Oh, Minion, you fantastic fish, you.
我们还等什么呢 快走
What are we waiting for? We'd better get going.
你还真骗倒我了
You got me.
- 好运 伙计们 - 我们要死了
- Good luck, fellas! - We're gonna die!
等等 你说什么
Wait, what?
嘿 曼城的衰人们 我在曼城之塔
Hey, Metro losers. This is Metro Tower.
人们说这是这城市力量的象征
They say it's supposed to be a symbol of our city's strength.
对我来说 却总是让我回想起
But for me, it's a reminder of the day
这个女人残忍的伤我的心的那天的伤心地 我讨厌伤心地
this woman ferociously ripped out my heart. And I hate reminders!
救命
Help!
请不要这样 我知道良心未泯 哈尔
Please don't do this. I know there's still good in you, Hal.
你太天真了 洛丝
You're so naive, Roxie.
你能看到所有人的优点 哪怕那人没优点
You see the good in everybody, even when it's not there.
你活的太理想化
You're living a fantasy.
复活节兔子 牙仙女什么的根本不存在
There is no Easter Bunny, there is no Tooth Fairy,
根本没有英国女王这回事
and there is no Queen of England.
这才是现实 你得醒醒了
This is the real world, and you need to wake up!
你敢挑战超级大坏蛋吗?
You dare challenge Megamind?
这塔容不下两个超级大坏蛋
This town isn't big enough for two super- villains!
哦 你的确是个坏蛋 但还不算超级大坏蛋
Oh, you're a villain all right! Just not a super one!
是吗 有什么区别吗?
Yeah? What's the difference?
闪亮登场!
Presentation!
- 我知道你会回来的 - 哦 我也是这么想的
- I knew you'd come back. - Well, that made one of us.
- 有什么计划吗? - 保命再说
- What's the plan? - Well, it mostly involves not dying.
这计划不错
I like that plan.
建筑物来了!
Building!
快点! 开快点!
Go faster! Make this thing go faster!
我控制不住!
I can't control it!
不
No.
这也太简单了
Well, that was easy.
还有一件事没完
Looks like there's only one loose end now.
拜托 好歹尊重一下公共交通嘛
Please, let's have a little respect for public transportation.
你回来了!
You came back!
你说对了洛克斯安 我不该离开的
You were right, Roxanne. I never should have left.
我以为你死了
I... I thought you were dead.
我的死亡是... 夸大了的
My death was... greatly exaggerated.
你就是传说中的那个阿飞啊
So, you're the punk I've heard about.
抱歉 我尽力了
I'm sorry. I did the best I could.
我为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
小跟班?
Minion?
惊喜吧!
Surprise!
他才是真正的英雄
He's the real hero.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind.
你去哪?
Going somewhere?
除了监狱?
Besides jail?
不 别打脸 哥们 拜托
No, not in the face, man. Please.
你知道应该怎么办 太阳神 离开蛮城!
If you know what's good for you, Tighten, you'll stay out of Metrocity!
- 明白了! - 永远地
- You got it! - For good!
你也太卑鄙了吧 姐
Pretty sneaky, sis.
管这个小镇叫"蛮城"的只有你了
But there's only one person I know who calls this town "Metrocity."
就你
You.
我猜你觉得这挺好玩的?
Bet you think it's really funny?
大家都在嘲笑一下这帅哥?
Let's all laugh at the really cool guy?
你嚣张不了多久的
Well, you're not gonna be laughing for long.
隐形车
The invisible car.
喂 记得我甩你的那天晚上吗
Hey! Remember that night that I dumped you?
你现在提这事?
You're bringing this up now?
我那天有回头的!
Well, I did look back!
你回头了? 你真的回头了?
You did? You did?
是啊 现在该你回头看看了
Yes! And you should look back right now!
哦 我懂了
Oh, I get it!
这是你最后一次耍我了
This is the last time you make a fool out of me!
我把你造成了英雄
I made you a hero.
干傻事的是你自己
You did the fool thing all by yourself.
你太可悲了
You're so pathetic.
不管你站在哪边 你总是败者
No matter what side you're on, you're always the loser.
当败者是有好处的
There's a benefit to losing.
你可以从失败中吸取教训
You get to learn from your mistakes.
哦 你别逗我了
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
小跟班 我要是活下来 我非杀了你不可
Minion, if I live, I will kill you.
好好飞吧
Enjoy your flight!
超级大坏蛋!
Megamind!
故事就是这么结束的
So this is how it ends.
一般 我会把它载入我光辉失败史的最后一页
Normally, I'd chalk this up to my last glorious failure.
但今天不行
But not today.
我还能说什么呢? 恶习难改
What can I say? Old habits die hard.
说再见吧 洛丝
Say bye- bye, Roxie.
喔罗
OIIo.
坏人呢 总是输的
The thing about bad guys, they always lose!
- 你做到了 你赢了 - 是啊...
- You did it. You won. - Well...
我终于找到了赢的理由 就是你
I finally had a reason to win. You.
小跟班!
Minion!
我看不见了 忽冷忽热 忽明忽暗的
Can't see. It's cold and... warm, and dark and light.
是我 小跟班 我在这
It's me, Minion. I'm right here.
我们两个一起经历这么多
We've had a lot of adventures together, you and I.
是啊 小跟班
We have, Minion.
我说 大多数都以失败收场
I mean... most of them ended in horrible failure,
可我们今天没输 是吧 先生
but we won today. Didn't we, sir?
是啊 小跟班 我们做到了 谢谢你
Yes, Minion, we did it. Thanks to you.
暗号 我们现在是好人了
Code: We're The Good Guys Now.
暗号 我想是的
Code: I Guess We Are.
哦 哦 哦 我要死了 我想 我快要死了
Oh, oh, oh, I'm going! I think this, this is it!
我要到那 遥远的...
I'm going... going far...
真是爱演戏啊
What a drama queen.
我现在觉得好多了 我想我只是需要游个泳而已
You know, I'm feeling much better now. I guess I just needed a swim.
他真吓到你了 是吧
He had you, didn't he?
小跟班的老把戏 别对我做这表情
Classic Minion. Don't give me that face.
他就是靠那张小脸骗人的
He reels you in with that little face.
- 看他那张老脸 - 我们做到了
- Look at that face. - We did it!
我们做到了
We did it!
- 拳头泵! - 你做到了
- Fist pump! - You did it!
我们赢了 我们赢了 我们赢了
We won, we won, we won!
回去吧 你个野蛮人
Get back, you savages!
抱歉 抱歉 他不太习惯人们积极的反应
Sorry! Sorry. He's just not used to positive feedback.
有趣 我觉得命运不是给我们的...
Funny, I guess destiny is not the path given to us...
...而是我们自己选择的
...but the path we choose for ourselves.
好了 把手抬起来
All right, put your hands in the air.
钱包交出来
Now hand over your wallets.
我开玩笑啦
I'm just kidding!
开玩笑
Just kidding!
我不得不承认 当好人是有好处的
I have to admit, being good has its perks.
知道吗 你穿白色很帅
You know, you look pretty good in white.
超级大坏蛋 麻烦你...
Megamind, if you plea...
喂 你挡着我孩子了
Hey. My kid can't see.
抱歉 朋友
Sorry, my friend.
你还有很长的路要走 我知道你
Way to go, little buddy. I knew he had it in him.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
超级大坏蛋 曼城的守护神
Megamind, defender of Metro City!
知道么 我喜欢这种声音
You know, I like the sound of that.
来吧!
Hit it!
超级大坏蛋! 超级大坏蛋! 超级大坏蛋! 超级大坏蛋!
Megamind! Megamind! Megamind! Megamind!
我是坏人 我是坏人 没错 耶
I'm bad! I'm bad! That's right. Yeah!
先生 你真得多清清你的口袋了
Sir, you really need to empty your pockets more often.
这是我一生里最糟糕的一天
This has been the worst day of my entire life.
别着急
No worries.